#大家好 我家的肉都吃完啦
Hi everyone! I have no more meat at home.
#現在摘點(青)菜來吃
So now I get some vegetables here.
#這個路邊的青菜 很靚的哦
The vegetables on the road side, are beautiful.
#有蘿蔔
There's radish,
#還有白菜
and Chinese cabbage too!
#你看 這個青菜 很漂亮的哦 這青菜
Look! This is, pretty, the veggies.
#很嫩的
Tender and juicy
#直接拔 連根拔起
Just pick it, root it out.
#這個 不知道誰家的
I've no ideas whose veggies they are.
#反正是我們村裡面的
But I don't care, as long as it's in our village.
#你看 這個夢蔔 還沒大哦
Look! This radish, is still small.
#那菜園裡面的應該 應該大啦
Those in the garden should be, should be larger.
#上次我們摘過的
We picked some there last time.
#我們下次再過來摘
Let's come again later.
#我現在去菜園裡面摘
I'll go to the garden first.
#你看 這裡還有夢蔔哦
Look! There's still some radish.
#這種蘿蔔很嫩的
This type of radish is very tasty.
#很好吃的 這種
It's tender and juicy, and it's,
#又嫩 (註︰又嫩又好吃又嫩)
juicy.
#那裡就遇有幾個了
There're still some inside.
#長得是比較丑一點 這種蘿蔔
It only looks a bit ugly, this radish.
#但是
But,
#沒有施過肥的哦 這個 (註︰我不太明白，沒施過時有甚麼值得炫燿？)
it has not been fertilized, the radish.
#哎喲 這個 長得那麼深
Ayo. The root, is so deep.
#我們再拔點這個黃豆回去
We'll pick some beans again.
#來都來啦
We're already here anyway.
#順便一起把它搬 搬回去
We can take, take them all back home.
#我家的貓
My kitten,
#它要跑到這菜園裡面來
runs into the garden.
#這有一個
Here's one.
#你看 現在都長胖好多啦
Look! It's now much fatter.
#肯定很好吃
It must be very tasty.
#你看
Look!
#有些都老啦
Some are already too old.
#不要那麼多
I don't need that much.
#搞一點點回去
I'll just take a bit.
#這個長得好飽滿啊
This is round and fat.
#在[SIC]過一個月就可以 (註︰以下六句很難譯呢，一句說話分成六段，加上口吃，由於中英詞序不同，所以口吃部份有更改)
It can all be picked,
#可以
picked
#這個 全部把它割回去
I mean, after a month
#用來
and then,
#用來哂一下 然後就變成
dried under the sun, to have the,
#黃豆
soybeans.
#好啦 現在我們回去啦
Alright! It's time to leave now.
#唉 多長兩個手多好啊
Ey! Why don't I have two more hands?
#只有兩個手 現在
Now I just have two,
#兩個手都裝滿啦
and they are already filled with stuff.
#都拿不到哇
I can't take anymore.
#把這個門
Restore the gate,
#放回原處哦
to the original position.
#讓別人看到
So that when people see it,
#讓別人不知道我進了裡面
nobody knows that I've been here.
#把這個黃豆哇 剝不來 來炒
The beans, take out the beans, and fry.
#很好吃的哦
It's tasty.
#小時候我們經常 經常都拿來炒
We used to fry, fry the beans, when we were kids.
#看來直接 直接蒸熟它 也很好吃的
But now we steam, just steam them. It's also tasty.
#這就是剝得太慢啦
Picking the beans takes too long.
#剝不快
It can't be fast.
#額 我洗一下
Eh! I wash,
#這個豆子
wash the beans.
#盆子太小啦
The pot is too small.
#等一下我們把這個豆子用油來炒一下
We'll then fry the beans with oil.
#用油炒一下然後放點 放點鹽
Fry with oil and then put some, some salt,
#就可以吃的 這個很好吃的哦
and then it can be served. It's tasty.
#你看 這個菜就搞好啦
Look! The dish is now ready.
#等一下就準備煮 我先把它放好在旁邊
I'll cook it in a while. Let me put it aside first.
#現在搞點這個蘿蔔
Now it's the turn of the radish.
#這個
It's,
#有點老哦 拿來餵豬
a bit old. Leave it for the pig.
#嗯 這個就好一點
Um! This one is better.
#你看 這3個菜
Look! The three dishes,
#這就我們中午要吃的
they'll be our lunch today.
#準備煮
Cooking time.
#好啦
Okay
#終於做好啦
It's done finally.
#哇
Wa!
#這豆子
The beans...
#嗯 好吃
Um! Tasty!
#看 今天的菜都沒花錢哦
Look! Not even a penny was spent on this meal.
#在农村就是好
It's only possible in a village.
#好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
#嗯 我要去盛飯啦
Um, I need to get the rice.